<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-20T00:36:53-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Mother of all Doughs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/sourdoughstater" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mother of all Doughs" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/sourdoughstater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/sourdoughstater"><![CDATA[<p>Making your very own sourdough starter is as easy as mixing flour and water. First what is a sourdough starter? A sourdough starter is a fermented mitxture of flour and water. The starter conatains colonies of living microorganisms such as yeast and lactobacilli. Just like any other living thing your starter will need food. But lets start with how you start a sourdough starter.</p>

<p>For a new starter you will need a glass jar(I use pasta sauce jars), flour (preferably whole wheat/rye and bread flour), and last but not least water(the tempature of the water depends on your home’s tempature. The hotter the room the cooler the water.). The fermentation of the flour will take about 7 days. Day 1 add 50grams of each whole wheat and bread flour, and 100ml of warm water into your jar. Mix together until there are zero dry spots; leave with the lid set on top(do not fully close)</p>

<p><img class="sub-image" src="/assets/images/raph.jpg" alt="Raphael" /></p>

<p>After 24 hours remove the lid and check for signs of fermentation in the form of bubbles at the top. A funky, acidic smell can be signs of the fermenetation starting. If zero bubbles are seen you can give it another 12-24 hours. Time to give your starter its first of many feedings. In a small mixing bowl pour in 100ml of water and 25grams of your starter. Mix together. Next add 50 grams of whole wheat flour and 50grams of bread flour. Mix together untill there are zero dry spots. clean out your jar and put the mixture in. Repeat daily</p>

<p>What do I do with the discard?!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making your very own sourdough starter is as easy as mixing flour and water. First what is a sourdough starter? A sourdough starter is a fermented mitxture of flour and water. The starter conatains colonies of living microorganisms such as yeast and lactobacilli. Just like any other living thing your starter will need food. But lets start with how you start a sourdough starter.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Easiest house plant to take care of</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/snakeplant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easiest house plant to take care of" /><published>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/snakeplant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/snakeplant"><![CDATA[<p>The snake plant is also known as Sansevieria is one of the easiest plants to take care of. They are native to Africa, Madagascar, and southern 
Asia. Snake plants have stiff upright leaves; which have gray, silver or gold edging. Given the room snake plants will grow pups(baby snake plants) that can be cut off after it developed its own roots.</p>

<p>Sansevieria is versatile when it comes to light. They have a huge range from low to bright light. This gives them the ability to grow almost anywhere in your home. They don’t need to be water that often let the soil dry then water well. I would check it every 2 days by sticking your finger in the soil to check if it is dry. They should be fed an all-purpose fertilizer every second month. I use a slow-release fertilizer.</p>

<p><img class="sub-image" src="/assets/images/snakeplant2.jpg" alt="Wu the snake plant" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The snake plant is also known as Sansevieria is one of the easiest plants to take care of. They are native to Africa, Madagascar, and southern Asia. Snake plants have stiff upright leaves; which have gray, silver or gold edging. Given the room snake plants will grow pups(baby snake plants) that can be cut off after it developed its own roots.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll" /><published>2020-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll"><![CDATA[<p>How to make your very own Jekyll site.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to make your very own Jekyll site.]]></summary></entry></feed>